Luna R. Siciliano

Portland. OR 97214 | 719-725-5135 | lunarsicliano@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Three years of experience in Ruby on Rails, React, and JavaScript based programming and a background in both science and art. My love for coding was realized while combining logic and artistic expression in full stack applications. I possess strong skills in communication, collaboration, and creativity that help companies deliver user interfaces that are unique, immersive, and engaging.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord, Object-Orientated Programming, HTML5, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, Firebase, Sanity.io, Heroku, JavaScript, React, p5.js, Three.js, TensorFlow.js, Microsoft Office, Procreate, Photoshop, Illustrator, Blender

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

The Void Becomes You - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

The Void Becomes You was created as an online space for anonymous catharsis.

- Created with React and Ruby on Rails as an API for the backend.
- Utilized PostgreSQL as an external database with Firebase hosting for backend technology.
- Integrated an animated background using p5.js using scalar animation.

U4iA - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

An image sharing application that lets users share and like posts anonymously.

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side. Employed Firebase image hosting to store uploaded user images.
- Implemented p5.js as a background using Perlin Noise.

The Internet - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

The Internet is an interactive art gallery that uses login functionality as a means of navigation.

- Styled with p5.js and three.js to create a unique and interactive UI.
- Face tracking via TensorFlow.js and live chat room to create an immersive experience.
- Created login forms that featured both full authentication using JWT as well "fake" login components.

EXPERIENCE

Production Club, Los Angeles, CA

Sr. Frontend Developer

8/30/2021- present

- Works with a team of graphic designers and project managers to make immersive single-page applications that showcase our past and upcoming work as three different companies using 2D and 3D design.
- Oversees three separate websites and makes sure they are compliant with ADA and zoning laws in the USA and EU.
- Creates and oversees the flow of UX with regard to attendee RSVP Experiences and Email notifications.
- Utilizes third party applications to be used inside of Webflow while also using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to create fully responsive websites and applications.

Ophidian Strength, Denver, CO

12/2019 - 03/2020

Owner

- Developed strength training regimens based on scientific research, client-specific needs and goals.
- Mentored, motivated, and assisted clients during their curated training session.

Anschutz Medical Center, Aurora, CO

12/2018 - 07/2019

Professional Research Assistant

- Performed different scientific tests to conduct research experiments in Head and Neck Cancers.
- Compiled and presented data based on scientific findings.

Grand Rapids Community College, Grand Rapids, MI

07/2014 - 10/2018

Professional Tutor

- Built study materials and lessons for the Biology Department and helped maintain the school's website.
- Taught diverse student study groups that focused on complex biological concepts.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Denver, CO Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and React immersive program	06/2021
Grand Valley State University, Grand Rapids, MI Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Science	12/2017
Kendall College of Art and Design, Grand Rapids, MI Courses completed towards a Bachelor of Arts, Illustration	08/2007 - 06/2009